<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Keith J Grant</title><link>http://keithjgrant.com</link><atom:link href="http://keithjgrant.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>JavaScript, CSS, UX, and the open web</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hosting on Github</title><link>http://keithjgrant.com/posts/hosting-on-github.html</link><description><![CDATA[
<p>Well, this is a bit of an experiment... I&#39;ve lost track of how many times I&#39;ve started a redesign of my WordPress blog, only to give up after days of fiddling.  This is kind of silly, since I generally finish the <em>design</em> of my site fairly quickly, but get held up fighting with the implementation minutae.</p>
<p>I blog very rarely.  I also occasionally want to host various other pages that don&#39;t necessarily need to fit with the theme of the rest of my site.  WordPress is really overkill for this.  What I really need is just some static hosting.  So I&#39;m giving GitHub Pages a try.  Not only that, but I should be able to play with the design whenever I feel like, without too much time investment.</p>
<p>So here&#39;s my new design.  It took me just a few days not only to build the site, but to also roll out some bare-bones blogging &amp; deployment scripts in gulp; my database is a git repository.  I can blog in <a href="http://jade-lang.com/">Jade</a> or MarkDown.  I think my wordpress days may be done, at least for now.</p>

]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://keithjgrant.com/posts/hosting-on-github.html</guid></item><item><title>Taming CSS</title><link>http://keithjgrant.com/posts/taming-css.html</link><description><![CDATA[
<p>Observation 1: Web developers, in general, don’t know CSS as well as they should.</p>
<p>Observation 2: There aren’t really any good roadmaps for learning all the essentials of CSS.</p>
<p>There are great resources for the basics, for styling, for code organization/architecture, for advanced tricks. But to work through them all, you get a lot of overlap, and they still leave you with missing gaps in your knowledge. Often, with CSS, you don’t know what you don’t know, and that makes it hard to move forward. My hope is to fix that, by putting them all together in one place.</p>
<p>Announcing <a href="https://github.com/keithjgrant/Taming-CSS">Taming CSS</a>, a CSS book for web developers.</p>

]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://keithjgrant.com/posts/taming-css.html</guid></item></channel></rss>