<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    
    <title>Keith J. Grant</title>
    
    <link>http://keithjgrant.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Keith J. Grant on Keith J. Grant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 08:42:36 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <link rel="hub"  href="https://keithjgrant.superfeedr.com/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" />
    <link rel="self" href="http://keithjgrant.com/index.xml" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" />
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://keithjgrant.com/notes/2017/02/84236/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 08:42:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://keithjgrant.com/notes/2017/02/84236/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Current status &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g0MLscghcN4&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g0MLscghcN4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://keithjgrant.com/notes/2017/02/105953/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 10:59:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://keithjgrant.com/notes/2017/02/105953/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are there any codemods to convert LESS to PostCSS/cssnext syntax? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be too fancy, just cut down on the busywork.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://keithjgrant.com/notes/2017/01/145158/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 14:51:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://keithjgrant.com/notes/2017/01/145158/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Progressive enhancement and rule of least power MATTER &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ArielleDRoss/status/825043489016705024&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/ArielleDRoss/status/825043489016705024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It’s Both</title>
      <link>http://keithjgrant.com/posts/2017/01/its-both/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 08:54:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://keithjgrant.com/posts/2017/01/its-both/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I’m a JavaScript developer. I have experience working in large web applications and dealing with the problems that come from scaling up. I studied Computer Science in college and love solving problems of software architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also (in case you &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.manning.com/books/css-in-depth&#34;&gt;somehow missed it&lt;/a&gt;) a “CSS Guy”. I learned CSS during its infancy in the mid-nineties and have worked to stay up to speed ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I look out at the industry today, it kind of feels &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/javascript-scene/jsx-looks-like-an-abomination-1c1ec351a918#1e2d&#34;&gt;like&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://mrmrs.io/writing/2016/03/24/scalable-css/&#34;&gt;watching&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zeldman.com/2017/01/03/kiss-my-classname/&#34;&gt;parents&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/thejameskyle/status/824795012680421376&#34;&gt;fight&lt;/a&gt;. And I’ll admit it, I’ve &lt;a href=&#34;http://keithjgrant.com/posts/2015/05/against-css-in-js/&#34;&gt;contributed to the problem&lt;/a&gt;. But the more I watch this unfold, the more I feel like we have two camps, talking right past one another, and no meeting in the middle. Both are missing the points the other is trying to make. So I’m shifting my stance:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-re-both-right&#34;&gt;We’re both right&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing SPAs is complicated business. The page isn’t just a static document you can slap some styles on and call it a day. What if you need to load content dynamically, and it results in unpredictable source order of your CSS? How do you know if styles for deeply-nested dependencies are already loaded? How do you know when you can delete code?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are hard problems. You can’t answer them by simply saying “learn CSS”. I personally may not like CSS-in-JS or inline styles, but I do realize they are important experiments. They are quests for answers to these issues. I don’t think they are the ultimate solution. That’s okay. Maybe they will get us to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, we have whole teams of developers who fundamentally don’t grok CSS. They code up their JavaScript components, then stick the styles they want into the project stylesheet. These may be great developers when it comes to traditional programming languages, but they get really frustrated with layout problems or specificity battles. Compound this with “too many cooks in the kitchen” and you have a real mess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have sixty-plus years of industry experience about architecting code in traditional programming languages, but we’ve struggled to apply this stuff to CSS. Only in the last seven years or so have we started to figure out best practices for the language, and we are not doing a great job of disseminating them. When we teach that BEM is a “naming convention” rather emphasize it is a way to architect systems with modular code, thousands of developers miss the point entirely. This only drives them further away because the so-called “best practices” don’t work when they aren’t actually followed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They don’t understand that BEM is about architecture, not simply namespacing. They don’t see the value of using a pattern library, of centralizing your CSS and imposing order on who controls the CSS rather than treating it like a garbage pile where any random dev can just add haphazard code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When JavaScript-centric developers hear, “putting your CSS in JavaScript makes it easier” they clamor to get on board. But this must be made absolutely clear: you still need to understand CSS. If you don’t know what a block formatting context is, CSS in JS will not fix your layout issues. If you don’t understand stacking contexts, you will continue to struggle with futile z-index battles. If you don’t learn custom properties or the difference between cascade and inheritance or margin collapsing, these experiments will not really solve the fundamental problem: most teams don’t know how to develop with CSS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;always-bet-on-del-javascript-del-the-open-web&#34;&gt;Always bet on &lt;del&gt;JavaScript&lt;/del&gt; the Open Web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, yes. Hire engineers who know how to deal with system architecture. But also &lt;a href=&#34;http://keithjgrant.com/posts/2016/10/your-team-needs-a-ux-engineer/&#34;&gt;hire someone exclusively for their CSS skills&lt;/a&gt;. Put smart people on your team from both camps. Let them work together to solve these problems. Because your problems are unique and your solutions might not look like someone else’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can say with confidence that CSS in JS will pass. In our industry, something new always comes along. The saying is, “Always bet on JavaScript” &amp;mdash; but this isn’t quite right. When it’s JavaScript vs Java or Ruby, yes, bet on JS. JavaScript wins not because it is inherently better; it wins because it is part of the open web platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The open web platform always wins. And CSS is part of that platform. It’s not CSS versus JS. It’s CSS &lt;em&gt;plus&lt;/em&gt; JS. The platform will evolve. And the platform will win.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://keithjgrant.com/replies/2017/01/102240/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 10:22:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://keithjgrant.com/replies/2017/01/102240/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I definitely avoid using the microformat classes as hooks for CSS. That can lock you into HTML structures that you might need to change later on. Honestly, I’d prefer if microformats used a different attribute altogether, but I think that ship has sailed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t mentioned anything about microformats in my book, though I could certainly point out this principle in more general terms &amp;mdash; try not to use the same classes as hooks for both JS and CSS, for instance (unless the two are inextricably linked to the same component).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, World Wide IndieWeb!</title>
      <link>http://keithjgrant.com/posts/2017/01/hello-indieweb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 15:34:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://keithjgrant.com/posts/2017/01/hello-indieweb/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It’s a new year, so it’s time for a new design! Only this time, the update is more than just a CSS revamp. This year, I join the “IndieWeb”. If you don’t know what that is, read on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me introduce you to the newest social network: it’s called the World Wide Web and it’s more than 25 years old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-decentralized-social-web&#34;&gt;The decentralized social web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social networks bother me. I don’t mean the privacy issues or mysterious sorting algorithms. Apart from these things, walled gardens are antithetical to the open standards that made the web successful in the first place. I can’t follow you on Facebook unless I have a Facebook account. You can’t like or reply to my tweet unless you join Twitter. The internet was founded on principles of decentralization, yet here we are, consolidating the bulk of our online activity into a small handful of sites we don’t control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have long wanted an open protocol to bring the key features of social networks (liking, commenting, sharing, following) out into the open web. Now, finally, I have discovered that a fair bit of progress has been made in this regard. The W3C now has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.w3.org/wiki/Socialwg&#34;&gt;Social Web working group&lt;/a&gt;, and their specifications are stabilizing and have even been &lt;a href=&#34;http://indieweb.org/&#34;&gt;adopted by many&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This redesign is my first step toward adopting these standards myself. I’ve completed phase one out of two (or possibly three) steps I want to take. Each one corresponds to a key piece of the “Social Web” protocols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;phase-i-webmentions&#34;&gt;Phase I: Webmentions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site now supports comments: you may comment on my blog by writing about it on your own blog. Then your blog should send mine a &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/Webmention&#34;&gt;webmention&lt;/a&gt;. These are similar to the old “pingbacks”, except they use a simpler format and they are an official &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.w3.org/TR/webmention/&#34;&gt;W3C Recommendation&lt;/a&gt;. (If your site doesn’t support webmentions, I’ve provided a little form where you can submit this yourself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They basically work like this: I write you a post. Then you write a post, with metadata indicating it is a response to my post. Your blog then tells my blog that you replied and provides the URL. If I want, I can then link to your reply. Both our posts now link to each other, and we each own our own data!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And because we are still beholden to some social networks, there is a service called &lt;a href=&#34;https://brid.gy/&#34;&gt;brid.gy&lt;/a&gt; that will find links to my post (and replies to those links) on Twitter or Facebook, and let my blog know about them, so I can log them here as comments. We can drag the old social network silos out into the open web!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;phase-ii-micropub&#34;&gt;Phase II: MicroPub&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next goal will be to incorporate something called MicroPub. This basically means I can write short posts (say, 140 characters), called Notes. I will use these notes to post replies to articles on the web. I can also syndicate these to twitter, where webmentions and brid.gy will help me track any conversation that happens there and link to it from my blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This involves a few more moving parts than phase I, but thankfully, most of the tools for this already exist as services online. I just need to wire things up and test them out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;phase-iii-activitypub&#34;&gt;Phase III: ActivityPub?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last piece of the puzzle for a decentralized social web is the whole subscribers/followers bit. The old concepts of RSS, PubSub, and feed readers can do this, but that model is more of a one-way publication, not a two-way street. There is a new approaches the W3C has been working on called ActivityPub that involves tracking followers and bringing more of the social network activities into this realm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This arena isn’t as mature yet, but I’ve certainly got my eye on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have high hopes for this will take us. It may take a while &amp;mdash; a couple years, at least &amp;mdash; but I think we will start to see more discussion happening in this arena. If you want to learn more about this stuff, checkout &lt;a href=&#34;http://indieweb.org/&#34;&gt;indieweb.org&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/plugins/indieweb/&#34;&gt;IndieWeb WordPress plugin&lt;/a&gt;. Hello, IndieWeb!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Talk About Separation of Concerns</title>
      <link>http://keithjgrant.com/posts/2016/12/separation-of-concerns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://keithjgrant.com/posts/2016/12/separation-of-concerns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s been a lot of talk lately about good old Separation of Concerns &amp;mdash; primarily in the context of React and the use of inline styles or CSS-in-JS. Advocates of these approaches argue that the language we use (be it JS, HTML, or CSS) is an arbitrary line to draw. And I would say: Yes, language is, for the most part, an arbitrary line. But that’s beside the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s get one thing straight. This&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;import styles from &#39;./tile.css&#39;;
...
render() {
  return &amp;lt;div className={styles.tile}&amp;gt;...&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;is architectually equivalent to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;render() {
  return &amp;lt;div className=&amp;quot;tile&amp;quot;&amp;gt;...&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latter approach, however:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;requires a drastically simpler build process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is both backwards- and forwards-compatible across all frameworks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doesn’t try to pretend that those styles exist in perfect encapsulated isolation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop championing CSS-in-JS as some ground breaking re-thinking of Separation of Concerns. It’s not. The React component will still inherit its font face, color, and size from a parent container. It still exists on the web platform, in an HTML document, where all the rules of styles and inheritance still apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can debate about class name collision, co-locating stylesheets, &lt;a href=&#34;http://keithjgrant.com/posts/css-first.html&#34;&gt;how styles fit into system archetecture&lt;/a&gt;, and other related topics. But let’s take this one off the table, because it’s a straw man argument.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Team Needs a UX Engineer</title>
      <link>http://keithjgrant.com/posts/2016/10/your-team-needs-a-ux-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://keithjgrant.com/posts/2016/10/your-team-needs-a-ux-engineer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, after I mentioned that I was the only one on my team that writes the CSS, someone replied, “You’re lucky”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It stuck with me, and I’ve been thinking about it since. The thing is, it’s not luck. It was a deliberate decision made early when the team was first put together. And I think the rest of the developers on my team would think themselves lucky for &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; having to touch the CSS. It is more valuable for us to have one person on the team who specializes in that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to rethink something about the way we build our web development teams. We spend a lot of effort hiring good programmers, but for the most part, they are interchangeable. We make sure that everyone we hire knows the fundamentals of software engineering, architecture, and the primary language the team uses. And then we &lt;em&gt;assume&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a developer has a solid grasp on JavaScript, we think, surely they know CSS. Surely they know how to deal with accessibility. Surely they have a grasp on how and when to use various HTML elements and aria-* properties. These are small beans compared to &lt;em&gt;the code&lt;/em&gt;. And in many ways, they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, of course, this isn’t how it plays out. Because we hire purely for the bigger task, CSS and accessibility always remain an afterthought. On most teams, nobody really knows what they are doing when it comes to these topics. They team stumbles along, joking amongst themselves how horrible CSS is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to fix this. On teams larger than four or five developers, I think we can: one person per team should be hired explicitly for these tasks. Most of the team will still be focused on JavaScript (or Python or Java). But one person&amp;mdash;call them a “CSS Developer” or “UX Engineer”&amp;mdash;should be hired specifically for these “afterthought” concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is a developer building a new component and needs some styles? The UX Engineer writes that CSS. The UX Engineer gives a snippet of HTML to the developer for them to incorporate into the component. The UX engineer ensures the correct semantics and can come alongside the developer to ensure keyboard navigation works. The UX Engineer maintains a pattern library for the team to use as a reference to find existing styles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This UX Engineer serves an important role, but furthermore, they allow the other developer to offload some work. The developer can focus on the &amp;ldquo;bigger concern&amp;rdquo; of getting the business logic right and ensuring the app works correctly. This improves the developer’s productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how things work on my team. I am effectively the UX Engineer, and I think everyone enjoys the process more because of it. In our case, we stumbled upon this setup&amp;mdash;I was originally hired for my JavaScript skills. As always, the CSS was an afterthought; I just happened to be good at it, so we settled into the current arrangement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t wait for your team to stumble into this. Set it up intentionally. Hire a UX Engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS in Depth</title>
      <link>http://keithjgrant.com/posts/2016/08/css-in-depth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://keithjgrant.com/posts/2016/08/css-in-depth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://keithjgrant.com/images/2016/css-in-depth-cover.png&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of CSS in Depth&#34; class=&#34;float-right&#34;/&gt;My book is finally for sale! The &lt;abbr title=&#34;Manning Early Access Program&#34;&gt;MEAP&lt;/abbr&gt; is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://manning.com/books/css-in-depth&#34;&gt;Manning’s website&lt;/a&gt;. The first three chapters are available now, and others will be rolling out steadily (I’ve actually already completed drafts of six chapters at this point).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until the end of August, you can use my code &lt;strong&gt;mlgrant2&lt;/strong&gt; for 50% off. Follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CSSinDepth&#34;&gt;@CSSinDepth&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter for updates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save Scoped CSS</title>
      <link>http://keithjgrant.com/posts/2016/06/save-scoped-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://keithjgrant.com/posts/2016/06/save-scoped-css/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update June 23, 2016:&lt;/strong&gt; The editor&amp;rsquo;s draft has been updated again. It looks like &lt;code&gt;@scope&lt;/code&gt; is gone for good, so this post is now a moot point. The way forward now lies in the Shadow DOM.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About &lt;a href=&#34;http://keithjgrant.com/posts/into-the-future-of-css.html#scoped-css&#34;&gt;a year ago&lt;/a&gt;, I wrote about a promising feature of CSS, scoping. I love the idea of this feature, and I think it could be one of the most important changes in the near future of CSS. You know all those complaints about “in CSS everything is global&amp;rdquo;? This feature is the answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I became excited recently when I noticed some movement in the W3C concerning this spec. So I took a look at what was going on. I found some good news, and I found some bad news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-good-news&#34;&gt;The good news&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://drafts.csswg.org/css-scoping/&#34;&gt;editor&amp;rsquo;s draft of the specification&lt;/a&gt; has recently been updated. The changes, I think, significantly improve the viability of the feature. They more closely resemble the hypothetical changes I wished for last year. Most importantly, scoped styles would no longer need to be defined inline in the HTML document; you can define scoped styles in an external stylesheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The proposed syntax looks like this, using a new &lt;code&gt;@scope&lt;/code&gt; at-rule:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34;&gt;@scope .foo-module {
  p {
    color: blue;
  }
}

@scope .bar-module {
  p {
    color: red;
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each scope is defined with a selector (&lt;code&gt;.foo-module&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.bar-module&lt;/code&gt;). This establishes a new scope for matched elements and their descendants. Inside the braces that follow, you can specify any styles you wish. These styles are then applied only to the elements belonging to that scope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the rules of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.w3.org/TR/css-cascade-3/#cascade-scope&#34;&gt;the cascade&lt;/a&gt;, rules applied to an inner scope will override those applied to an outer scope, &lt;em&gt;regardless of their selector specificity&lt;/em&gt;. This is precisely the behavior CSS-in-JS and/or CSS Modules users want! And yes, this definition is in the current Candidate Recommendation of the spec.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means, given the example above, a &lt;code&gt;foo-module&lt;/code&gt; inside a &lt;code&gt;bar-module&lt;/code&gt; will have blue text; and a &lt;code&gt;bar-module&lt;/code&gt; inside a &lt;code&gt;foo-module&lt;/code&gt; will have red text. This could solve so many developer frustrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-bad-news&#34;&gt;The bad news&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got excited when I saw these changes, so I started reading more on what prompted them. I discovered that it is a sort of last-ditch effort to salvage the spec. The problem? Browser vendors have shown no interest in implementing it. Firefox has long-since implemented the earlier version of the spec, but that&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we developers want this feature, we need to let the browser vendors know. Otherwise, it&amp;rsquo;s DOA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So tell them, please. Follow these links, and up-vote or leave comments in support of scoped styles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/a/chromium.org/forum/#!searchin/blink-dev/scoped/blink-dev/R1x18ZLS5qQ/Bjuh_cENhlQJ&#34;&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wpdev.uservoice.com/forums/257854-microsoft-edge-developer/suggestions/14895573--scope&#34;&gt;Edge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a channel for Safari. If you know where it is, please let me know and I&amp;rsquo;ll add it here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s not allow this to die.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
